If you are wealthy,
understand that it has been given to you so that
you can give it to those who are less so.
If you are smart, then use it to serve.
Look at people in society who are much
less smart than you,
who can't work things out for themselves.
Stand up so that you can be the strength to
others who can't stand up on their own two feet.
And then they will hold on to you when you
stand,
because they just don't have the courage,
the guts to stand up on their own.
They'll want you, they'll need you to
carry them forward.
And don't stop, because if you stop,
they'll all stop.
There are those who look up to you for
inspiration.
There are those who are still alive because they
look at you and they feel like life is living.
Sometimes you don't even know these
things.
know, if you can become someone like that,
that's really a life worth having lived.
These are the greatest ambitions in life.
If you can live to give life to others,
that's a great life, isn't it?