What do you call a good relationship is?
Is it a sacrifice or something that you
gain out of it?
Each and every relationship, what do you
expect?
What do you get out of it?
Have you ever thought about it?
purpose of having a relationship.
Let's take the employee-employer
relationship that you have at your office.
If you look at it, that is based on the
expectation.
always get in a relationship to fulfill
our expectations.
To maintain a good relationship, we expect
things from the other person.
And if it's being fulfilled, we call it a
good relationship.
If it's not, it's a scattered one.
You have a set of expectations that you
want to fulfill from that person.
That's why we maintain relationships in
life.
the problems people face,
anxiety, depression, or whatever the problem that you have to face in order, you
see, like, what happens in the outside world doesn't bring you either happiness or worry.
It all depends on expectation.