How to achieve a stress-free work-life
balance?
I mean, some of you maybe are like
struggling with the problems in life,
especially with your work life and your
personal life.
Because those are two things that actually
you have to have a balance in your life,
otherwise your life becomes a mental hell,
isn't it?
But before we discuss into that topic, how
are you doing everyone?
I hope you are doing fine.
I hope you are doing well.
Ladies and gentlemen,
here I won't actually tell you what to do,
but here I'll tell you what happens behind our stress.
Then you'll actually realize what to do and
how to apply this formula in your life.
I mean, other than taking each and every
scenario in your life,
here I'm just dropping the formula of
stress, the formula of happiness.
Then by applying that formula into your
life,
you can become or you can actually make
that situation stressful or happy.
It's up to you now because you have the
formula.
So, this is the formula.
Formula is just two letters.
Pi x.
Nothing else.
Life equals pi x.
Pi, what is pi?
Pi is a constant in maths.
Pi is a constant.
It never changes.
I mean we have something like 22 over 7
and we have 3.1423 and it keeps going, isn't it?
It's a constant.
And we have x.
x is the variable.
Variable is actually what you can change.
You can give a value to a variable.
Let x equals 5.
Let x equals 10.
You can change the variable.
Because it's a, again, variable.
But constants cannot be changed.
Pi is pi.
No matter where you put it, how you put
it, pi is pi.
Isn't it?
In life, we have pis and x.
Pi are the life situations where they are
constants.
They cannot be changed.
You failed an exam.
That's a constant.
can't change it.
Your favorite team loses a match.
It's a constant.
It cannot be changed.
You get a flat tire.
It's a constant.
It cannot be changed.
Your loved ones gives you up, dumps you.
It's a constant.
It cannot be changed.
You're having a breakup.
It's a constant.
It cannot be changed.
In life, we have constants.
The things that you can't change.
And also we have x, the variable.
There is only one variable.
That is expectation.
The output of the formula, life equals pi
x, is happiness or sadness.
Calmness or stress.
That is the output of the formula pi x.
And depend on not just constants,
but also the variable, the output is
different.
Here, the constants are the life facts,
but the expectation on those things actually define
whether the happiness would be derived or the sadness.
You having a flat tire actually just doesn't
mean that it gives you sadness or stress.
Your expectations actually define whether you
would feel stressed out of that situation.
It's up to the expectation part.
The thing is actually you can't change the
life constant.
I mean, there's a way to be happy.
Either you change the constant by keeping
the same expectation.
If you change the constant, again you get
whatever the desired outcome.
Let's take F equals M.
And here you change the mass.
If you change the mass,
then the force would be changed, though
you have the same acceleration.
But also what you can do,
you can have the same mass, But increased
acceleration, again the force changes.
Like that, life equals pi x.
Your happiness, your sadness,
your stress, your jealousy, everything
depends on this pi x part.
If you're pi, you can't change the pi.
You can't change the pi.
You can't change the life situations.
You have to have them.
You're getting blamed.
You're getting criticized.
You're getting demeaned.
giving you a hate comment for your posts.
Those are constant, they cannot be
changed.
You are playing a game and all of a sudden
your character is fired and he is dead.
If you feel sadness or stress now, it's
not the constant but the expectation.
I mean you trust your friend
wholeheartedly but finally your friend betrays you.
Your wife betrays you, your girlfriend,
boyfriend betrays you.
Behind the scenes, they are having their
own secret lives.
And you get to know about them through
your friends or some other way.
Now, if your world falls apart, that's a
problem.
Not with the life constant.
Not with the life constant, but with the
variable expectation.
If the life constant,
let's take your boyfriend, your boyfriend cheats on you, let's
take secretly he's cheating on you and he's having another affair.
If that incident gives sadness,
if that incident is the source of sadness, then how can the
other person be happy due to the fact that you are cheated on?
How can the other person be happy due to
the fact that you are cheated on?
Because that life constant doesn't mean
sadness or happiness.
Life constant is just neutral events in
the world.
They don't mean anything.
They don't mean happiness or sadness or
anything.
It depends on the expectation.
All the time life is like that, ladies and
gentlemen.
Life is always like that.
That's why everyone doesn't love the same
music,
everyone doesn't love the same genre,
everyone doesn't love the same artist.
Though they hear the same thing,
the feelings that derived, the feelings
which arose in their mind, completely different.
Depend on expectations all the time.
Therefore, don't blame the world or don't
love the world as well.
Because the world cannot make you stress
or calm.
It's a mental fabrication which is
fabricated in your mind.
Then don't point your finger out into the world
saying that you make me happy, you make me sad.
That's not a fact in the world, that's not
something in the world.
You can't give the credit to the world
about it.
It's about you give the credit to
yourself.
When you next day that you eat a really,
really, really delicious ice cream, you give the
credit to your mind, not to the ice cream.
Wow!
Super mind.
Not just that, super expectation.
Not just that, super vexation.
Super suffering.
to the suffering only you feel happiness.
If there is no suffering,
no happiness, that's why you can't keep
eating the same ice cream.
If the ice cream gives you happiness, then
your happiness should be increased.
Since the ice cream doesn't give you
happiness,
but the reason for vexation gives you happiness, that's why
you feel bored after some time of having ice cream.
Therefore, ladies and gentlemen,
what I'm telling is actually, Life, don't blame
the life for whatever you go through today.
Stress, I understand.
People who have stress, I really
understand you.
I know how painful it is.
I know how you feel.
I can understand you.
But the thing is actually I'm in your side
and I'm telling you by being next to your side,
next to you, I mean you don't have to go
through this.
The reality is actually if you can
eradicate the expectation,
That is the real formula for happiness.
The thing is actually, then you only have
constants.
you don't have X, life equals Pi.
Life equals, not happiness, not sadness or
anything.
Life equals Pi.
You just experience sight, sound, smell,
taste and touch.
Don't you want to achieve that mental
state?
We call that supreme bliss of Nibbana,
Now, but don't just give the word.
At mental state, don't even achieve it.
Just life, you are okay with anything in
life.
Anything in life, anything in the world.
Because life equals pie, because there's
no variable expectation.
There's a way to achieve it, ladies and
gentlemen.
Now, whatever you go through, I am really
sorry for what you go through.
And I don't want you to have that.
Your tear that you have on your eye,
I don't want to see any tears from your
eyes.
I'm here to help you to completely
eradicate all the tears, all the frowns.
Just have a smile on the face forever.
There's a way and a path for that.
Come with us and we'll show you the path.
Therefore, keep that in your mind.
I hope this would help you to achieve
stress-free life and have a nice day.
May the Nau Bhattiparjam bless you.