Am I better than him?
Am I less than him?
Am I richer?
Am I more good-looking than her?
These are the comparisons that always run
in people's minds.
See, someone who wishes to be good-looking
is never happy within,
because they're always comparing
themselves.
I would never wish this upon your
daughters.
Someone who is beautiful within doesn't compare
their looks with another person, their content.
you like white, you're only happy when you
see white,
you're unhappy when you see black.
But if you like neither black nor white,
now you see the beauty in both of them.
When you have an image of what beauty is
like,
you are only happy with half of this
world.
The other half cannot make you happy.
If you like long hair, short hair makes
you unhappy.
If you like neither, then you see the
beauty in both.
But to you, half of it is beautiful, the
other half is ugly.
When you see ugly, and you keep doing that
until you see beauty.
It brings you happiness, doesn't it?
I don't need that, because I have found
beauty within.
So show me anything and I'll be happy with
that.
Stop showing me anything, I'll be happy
with that.
Unconditional happiness, that's what we
need.