The noble association is the key, dear
ladies and gentlemen.
That's why I told you I have the key and I
want to hand over that key to you.
Because I cannot unlock on behalf of you.
the keyhole is in your side.
you have to unlock by yourself.
That's why as in Matrix, I'm giving you
two pills now.
Red pill and blue pill.
If you take the red pill, you can come out
of the mental asylum.
That you all are locked in since you were
born.
Don't you think your perception is a
deception?
It's a deception.
You don't perceive the world as it is.
You always perceive the world as what?
You deceive.
You get deceived because of the ignorance.
want you to come out of this jail.
Hurry up.
There's not much time left, dear ladies
and gentlemen.
life is too short.
are spending a valuable human life.
Hurry up.