If I ask about your job,
you may say that I'm a doctor, I'm an
engineer, I'm an accountant, I'm a lawyer.
You will say all these things, but
actually your job is, can you guess?
You are a servant.
I can't use the other word.
If you are not offended, then I will say,
you are a slave of your mind.
That's what you do.
You didn't want to go to school, you know
that.
You wanted to play, but you had to go to
school.
You had to get good education, and you got
it.
You got your PhD.
With that certificate, you applied for a
job.
Then you found it.
And you start your journey from there.
You started earning money.
did you do with that money?
How much money do you have in your account
now?
Each time you earn money, you had to
spend.
Because when you see something, when you
hear something, your mind is vexed.
Because you think that,
that movie, that picture, that scenery,
whatever it is, it's so pleasurable.
That's how you thought.
As soon as you think about it, your mind
is vexed.